{"Topic": "Rocks and Minerals", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Which one among the following rocks does not belong to the same group?", "op1": "Shale", "op2": "Limestone", "op3": "Slate", "op4": "Sandstone", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The Deccan Trap Formation was caused by", "op1": "Shield eruption", "op2": "Composite eruption", "op3": "Caldera eruption", "op4": "Flood basalt eruption", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In which among the following terrains the bore wells and canals can be dug easily?", "op1": "Gneiss, granites and basaltic terrain of Peninsular India", "op2": "Rolling and dotted hilly terrain of North-east India", "op3": "Soft alluvium of the Northern Plains", "op4": "Confined aquifer below the normal water table", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The Damuda series of Gondwana system has three stages, namely, Raniganj, Barren Rocks and Barakar. The middle stage is called Barren because", "op1": "it consists of coal and not iron", "op2": "it consists of iron and not coal", "op3": "it consists of neither coal nor iron", "op4": "it is a sedimentary layer consisting of shale and clay", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following statements is/are correct?", "op1": "1,  2  and  3", "op2": "3  only", "op3": "1  and  2  only", "op4": "2  and  3  only", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "ect the correct answer using the code given below:", "op1": "Sedimentary", "op2": "Igneous", "op3": "Metamorphic", "op4": "None of the above", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which one among the following is a primary rock?", "op1": "1  and  2  only", "op2": "1,  2  and  3", "op3": "3  only", "op4": "1  only", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following statements regarding the Deccan Trap is/are correct?", "op1": "1  only", "op2": "2  only", "op3": "Both  1  and  2", "op4": "Neither  1  nor  2", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "ect the correct answer using the code given below:", "op1": "Basalt", "op2": "Silica", "op3": "Shale", "op4": "Magnesium", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Consider the following statements about rocks:", "op1": "under the mountain ranges", "op2": "under continental masses", "op3": "at ocean bottoms", "op4": "at mid-oceanic ridges", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "ch of statements given above is/are correct?", "op1": "sediments", "op2": "liquid rock", "op3": "magma", "op4": "lava"}, {"Question": "Which one of the following is generally found in sedimentary rocks?"}, {"Question": "The earth\u2019s crust is the thinnest"}, {"Question": "Which of the following rocks is different from others?", "op1": "marble", "op2": "gypsum", "op3": "sandstone", "op4": "limestone", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Magma that cools slowly beneath the earth's surface produces", "op1": "marble.", "op2": "intrusive igneous rocks.", "op3": "fine-grained metamorphic rocks.", "op4": "extrusive igneous rocks.", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Igneous, sedimentary, and metamorphic rocks are usually composed of", "op1": "intergrown crystals", "op2": "minerals", "op3": "fossils", "op4": "sediments", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which process is necessary for the formation of igneous rocks?", "op1": "erosion", "op2": "deposition", "op3": "metamorphism", "op4": "solidification", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which characteristic of rocks tends to increase as the rocks are metamorphosed?", "op1": "density", "op2": "porosity", "op3": "permeability", "op4": "number of fossils present", "Answer": 3}]}